http://www.litandphil.org.uk/privacy-policy/

1 Introduction
The Literary & Philosophical Society of Newcastle upon Tyne (“the Society) needs to collect and use certain types of information (“personal data”) about its members, staff, volunteers, supporters and sponsors (“the data subjects”) in order to carry on its activities. Personal data must be collected and dealt with in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (EU Regulation 2016/679) and the Data Protection Act 2018.
2 Collection, processing and use
(a) The Society will take all necessary measures to ensure that it will be able to adhere to the Principles in Article 5 of the Regulation and the six data protection principles in sections 86 to 91 of the Act.
(b) When collecting personal data, the Societywill tell the data subject what the data will be used for.
(c) The Society will ensure that personal data will be–
stored securely;
accessible only to authorised staff and authorised volunteers;
kept up to date;
corrected if requested by the data subject;
retained for only as long as either–
needed for the purpose for which the data was collected or a purpose to which the data subject has since consented, or
required or permitted by law to be retained;
disposed of in accordance with the Regulation and the Act.
(d) The Society will maintain a procedure for responding to a request from a data subject for access to personal data held by the Society, and will provide a copy of the procedure to any data subject who requests one.
3 Disclosure
The Society will not disclose personal data to another person unless–
the data subject consents, or
the law requires or permits disclosure without consent.
For events, news & offers...
Sign up to our e-newsletter
(You can unsubscribe at any time)
Sign up today
Home
Privacy Policy
